前情提要
人们一直问东问西的  我根本不知道答案
They people keep asking me questions I don't know the answer to.
现在手握机枪的是我们
It's us that have the machine guns now
焦头烂额的是他们
and it's them that's in the mud.
枪支  谢尔比先生  我们愿意出大价钱
Guns, Mr Shelby. We'd pay good money.
你们是代表谁在谈
For who do you speak?
爱尔兰共和军
The Irish Republican Army.
你是什么人  警察吗
What are you? A copper?
你因为他是爱尔兰共和军才跟踪他
You went after him because he was IRA.
我跟着他是因为我以为他身上有情报
I followed him because I thought he might have information.
卧底最难的一点就是
The difficulty with undercover work,
时刻谨记自己是谁  格蕾丝
Grace, is to remember what you are.
你妹妹在里面生孩子
Your sister's in there giving birth.
有个男人该待在这里
There's one man who should be here.
你说的对  波莉  我发誓
You are right, Poll. On my oath.
告诉弗莱迪来这里没事
Tell Freddie it's safe.
欢迎来到这个世界  儿子
Welcome to the world, son.
弗莱迪
Freddie?
波莉
Pol!
但警察把他的父亲抓走了
The police came and took his father away!
你个骗子
You liar!
丹尼尔·欧文
浴   血
黑   帮
第一季   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第五集
开门吧  亲爱的
Open up, love.
我给你和孩子带了点东西来
I brought more things for you and the baby.
我带了新鲜鸡蛋和面包
I've got some fresh eggs and bread...
我把东西放在门口
I'll leave it here.
艾达  多替孩子想想
Ada, think of the little one.
孩子可没有原则
Babies don't have principles.
你跟她说话了吗
Did you speak to her?
她没有回应
She didn't speak back.
你告诉她了吗
Well, did you tell her?
我只会告诉她我确定的真相
I'll only tell her what I know to be true.
我最后再说一遍
It's the last time I am going to say this.
出卖弗莱迪·索恩的人不是我
It wasn't me who shopped Freddie Thorne.
汤米
Tommy...
我让你对着圣经发誓
I'd ask you to swear on the Bible,
但你做不到  对吗
but you can't swear on that, can you?
你对任何东西都毫无敬畏
Nothing you hold is sacred.
我泡了茶
There's tea.
新的运作体系
The new system...
所有事都记在日记里  对吗
..everything in the diary, eh?
一颗黑星  这是什么意思
A black star? What does that mean?
标上黑星那天
The black star day...
是我们除掉比利·肯波和他的手下的日子
..is the day we take out Billy Kimber and his men.
没人知道这事
No-one knows this!
你的家人都不知道吗
Not even your family?
格蕾丝
Grace...
我的所有家人都讨厌我
..everyone in my family hates me.
我为何还要告诉他们
Why would I tell them?
他彻底失控了  就是这么回事
He's off the bloody rails, is what he is.
如果他背叛自己最好的兄弟
If he'll turn nose on his best mate...
该死的邻居们  约翰  背后打小报告
Bloody neighbours, John. Snitch behind the curtain.
如果你这么想  那恐怕世上只有你一个人如此
If you think that, you're the only one who does.
看看这个  看看  生意很红火啊
Look at this, look. Bloody raking it in.
谁在管理这个马戏团
Who's running this carny?
一个叫马斯顿的人
Name of Marston.
准备利用这个拳击场在小希斯度过寒冬
Intends on wintering in Smallheath with this ring.
-是嘛  -难道他没听说过
- Does he! - Ain't he heard
要想在小希斯落脚
nobody in Smallheath craps in a pot
必须经过汤米大神同意吗
without the decree of Tommy Almighty?
马斯顿先生  对吧  拳击场的老板
Mr. Marston, I believe? The ringmaster?
我骄傲地回答  正是在下
Proud I am to say so.
很好  那先来文明地谈谈
Yes, well, these here are civilised parts.
想要在这里做让人互相打架的生意
Man wants to set his stall up with fellas lamping each other,
你得先拿到许可证
he needs himself a licence.
许可证
A licence.
交钱才能拿  给管事的人
For a fee. From those in charge.
我看不如这样吧
I'll tell you what.
我留着我赚到的钱
How about I keep my money,
你把你的许可证塞回自己的屁眼里
and you shove a licence up your arsecrack?
你最好别这么跟我说话
You don't want to speak to me like that.
你他妈以为自己是谁啊
And who the bloody hell do you think you are?
我叫亚瑟·谢尔比
My name is Arthur Shelby.
爸爸
Dad?
天啊
Jesus.
谢谢  真是个乖孩子
Thank you. You are a good boy.
多谢您  上帝
Bless you, Father,
感谢你赐予我们食物
for these bounties we are about to receive...
老天啊
Jesus Christ...
拜托  女人
Please, woman...
不要渎神
..not in vain.
吃完你的三明治就赶紧走人
Finish your sandwich and sling your hook.
波莉安娜
Pollyanna.
我是一家之主的客人
I'm the guest of the head of this family,
你就让我好好做客
so why don't you let me
自己去熨熨衣服买买菜吧
tend to your mangle or your scuttle?
一家之主没在家
The head of the family ain't here.
汤米  他有时帮我管理生意
Tommy... he sometimes helps me with business.
说曹操曹操到
Well. Speak of the devil.
你好吗  儿子
How are you, son?
滚出去
Get out.
好啦  儿子  我已经洗心革面了
Come on, son. I'm a changed man.
这个家十年前需要你的时候
This family needed you ten years ago
你头也不回地走了
when you walked out on this.
现在不欢迎你  滚出这个家
Not now. Get out of this house.
汤米  他已经改过了
Tommy, he's different...
你闭嘴
You shut up.
没事的  儿子
It's all right, son.
亚瑟·谢尔比不会待在不被欢迎的地方
Arthur Shelby never stays where he is not welcome.
你现在真是个人物了
Quite something you've become.
再见  儿子
Bye, son.
他是我们的爸爸
He's our dad.
他是个自私的混蛋
He's a selfish bastard.
你说别人是自私的混蛋
You calling someone a selfish bastard?
有点可笑吧  汤米
That's a bit rich, Tommy.
都是因为你
I mean, thanks to you...
我们已经失去一个妹妹了
..we're already down a bloody sister.
你想要见他  亚瑟
If you want to see him, Arthur?
你想要见他  那你跟他一起走
You want to see him? You can go with him.
格蕾丝
Grace...
我拿五镑的零钱  行吗
I am taking five pounds from petty cash all right?
那里的零钱不够五镑
We don't have five pounds in petty cash.
那我就有多少拿多少
Then I'll take what we've got.
数一下有多少  留个收据
Count it and leave a receipt.
亚瑟  有些账目我不太明白
Arthur, there are some things in the books that I don't understand.
-我也一样  -我们每周都给伦敦一个叫
- Likewise. - Every week we pay one pound and ten shillings
丹尼尔·欧文的人汇一英镑十先令过去
by postal order to a "Daniel Owen" In London.
高速炮弹丹尼
Danny Whizz Bang,
帮我们在卡姆登镇码头的酒吧里探听消息
hangs round the pubs in Camden Town Wharf for us.
他耳听八方
He keeps his ears open for business.
是个好人
He's a good man.
高速炮弹丹尼不是死了吗
I thought Danny Whizz Bang was dead.
那你就错了
Then you thought wrong, didn't you?
但我见过他的坟墓  他中枪而死
But I've seen his grave. He was shot.
那是演给意大利人看的
That was a show to satisfy the wops.
汤米开枪射出的是羊脑
Tommy just shot some sheep's brains at him.
那墓里葬的是谁
Who is buried in his grave?
格蕾丝  你要是明白事理的话
Now look, Grace, if you know what's good for you,
就别问与你无关的问题
you don't ask questions about things that don't concern you.
永远别问
Never. Right!
这钱给你
And that's for you.
别告诉汤米我拿了这些钱
And don't tell Tommy I took this.
要我说的话  那孩子需要个藏身之所
The boy needs a good hiding, if you ask me.
波莉阿姨也算能保护他吧
Yeah, well, Aunt Polly's close to giving him one.
貌似还有约翰和艾达
John and Ada too, it sounds like.
约翰整天都在抱怨规矩
John moans on bloody principle -
但要是你见过他的夫人...
but if you saw his Mrs...
你有女人了吗  儿子
You have a girl yourself, son?
得让汤米满意  是吗
P'raps when it suits Tommy, eh?
战后他整个人都变了
Yeah, well... He's been different, you know, since the war.
是啊  战争会改变一个人
Yeah, well... The war can change a man.
我是在说我自己
Speaking for myself, anyway.
你在哪打过仗  爸爸
Where did you fight, Dad?
到处都打过  儿子
All over, son, all over.
是啊  到处
Yeah, all over.
接着耶稣拯救了我
Then the salvation of Jesus Christ spread his light over me,
我作为朝圣者  去了新世界
and, as a pilgrim, I come to visit the New World...
美国
America.
在那里  我见到了未来
Where I beheld the future.
赌场简直是金钱工厂  儿子
Casinos! Money factories, son.
我一直在研究赌场
Look, I've been studying the competition,
他们的骗局和运营系统
their schemes, their systems.
-看啊  都在这里  -让我看看
- Look at that... It's all there. - Show me.
那行业简直是暴利
There's a fortune to be made here.
我已年老体衰  我的心脏就是个破旧的容器
I'm an old man, and my heart's a battered vessel.
但里面  仍搏动着梦想
But within...There still beats the fluttering pulse of a dream...
谢尔比赌场和酒店
The Shelby Casino and Hotel...
全世界的人都会蜂拥而来
Gents and dames will come flocking from all corners -
纽约  芝加哥  波士顿
New York, Chicago, Boston -
都会来到谢尔比的地盘  在那里
to The Shelby, where I can stand proudly
我可以与我的孩子们并肩而立
with my dear children by my side.
而里面的女人
And the women there!
如新鲜蜜桃一般
Like fresh peaches.
要多少有多少
Thou could have a dozen.
我们都会成为国王
We'd all of us be kings!
办赌场要多少钱
How much, how much to get started?
只需一点本钱  就能长成摇钱树
The oak needs but an acorn.
我们干吧
Let's do it.
开干吧
Let's do it. Let's bloody do it.
我也非常渴望
It would make my heart beam...
但我不想引起你们兄弟不和
but I don't want to cause any discord between the brothers.
不如你先去跟汤米谈谈
So, please, why don't you talk to Tommy first...?
我已经受够听他吩咐了
I'm sick of taking orders from him.
汤米可不是这个家族仅有的生意脑袋
Tommy's not the only one in the family with a head for business,
谢尔比家族的钱是大家共用的
and Shelby money is Shelby money.
感谢上帝给了我这么出色的儿子们
I thank God for my wonderful sons.
必须得庆祝一番
This is cause for a celebration!
-干杯  -干杯
- Slange. - Slange.
站起来  战士
On your feet, soldier!
站起身
On your feet.
爸爸  我不想跟你对打
Dad, I don't want to fight you, Dad.
拜托  孩子  我这年纪都能做你爸爸了
Come on, boy! I'm old enough to be thy father.
-揍他  -对  揍他
- Hit him! Hit him! - That's it! Hit him!
站起来啊
On your feet.
快起来
Get up.
好吧
All right!
就是这样
That's it!
你就这点本事吗  孩子
Is that all you've got, boy?
站起来
Get up.
这位是小亚瑟·谢尔比  我儿子
This here is Arthur Shelby Junior! My son.
我爱他  为他骄傲
I love him, and I'm proud of him,
他能和在场随便哪个人搏斗
and he can fight any one of yous in here.
打得漂亮  儿子  干得好
You did good, son. You did good.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad. I love you.
是谢尔比先生吗
Mr Shelby?
你哪位
Who's asking?
我叫波恩
My name is Byrne.
我听你在卡姆登镇的人说你要谈判
I had word from your man in Camden Town that you wanted to parley.
那就谈吧
Then parley it is.
几个月前有个叫莱恩的人来这里
A few months ago a man named Ryan came to this place with
想从你那里买点好东西
a view to buying some goods from you.
莱恩先生遇害了  中枪而亡
Mr Ryan met with an accident. He was shot.
-我听说了  -他这人心直口快  我知道
- I heard... - He was a man with a quick mouth. I know that.
我在想他有没有在这里树敌
I wondered if he had made any enemies in here.
据我所知没有
None that I know of.
这里似乎不是树敌的地方
It's not the kind of place to make enemies.
这里来者便是客  波恩先生
All are welcome here, Mr Byrne...
包括爱尔兰人吗
Including Irish?
尤其是爱尔兰人
Especially Irish.
莱恩告诉你他是爱尔兰共和军的一员
Ryan told you he was a member of the Irish Republican Army.
他还是客吗
Was he still welcome?
正如我所说  来这里买酒喝的都是座上客
Like I say, any man that buys beer is welcome.
也许你不相信他
Perhaps you didn't believe him.
人们有时会在酒吧吐露真言
In pubs sometimes people say things
有时只是酒后胡言
and sometimes it's the whisky talking.
很难分辨二者
It's hard to tell which is which.
作为一个滴酒不沾的人  我觉得这点很有意思
As a teetotal man I find it amusing.
除非是以悲剧收场
Except when it ends in tragedy.
要来点加水的甜香酒吗  波恩先生
Would you like some cordial and water, Mr Byrne?
谢尔比先生  莱恩虽然心直口快
You see, Mr Shelby, Ryan, for all his quick mouth,
但却与我们...
was indeed connected.
我们是非常亲密的...兄弟
Very well connected...to our brotherhood.
既有血缘关系又是伙伴  他是我表弟
By membership and blood. He was my cousin.
我来自南阿玛
I am from South Armagh.
我在那里也算颇有影响
I am a man of influence there.
来点甜酒和水不错  谢尔比先生
Cordial and water would be grand, Mr Shelby.
格蕾丝  拿些水和甜酒到雅间来
Grace. Bring some water and cordial to the snug.
是  谢尔比先生
Yes, Mr Shelby.
我表弟来买枪
My cousin came to buy guns.
我告诉他我没枪
And I told him I had none.
你的人丹尼·欧文一喝醉就爱说话
Your man Danny Owen talks a lot when he's drunk.
他说剃刀党有枪
He says the Peaky Blinders do have the guns.
从这条路上的那家工厂抢来的
Robbed from the factory down the road.
他还吹嘘有一堆刘易斯机枪
He boasts about a stack of Lewis machine guns.
还有足够的子弹带  多到能给上帝当裤腰带
And enough belts of ammunition to hold up God's trousers.
是啊  听起来像是我们的丹尼没错
Yep. That sounds like our Danny.
他就爱瞎想象
He has an imagination.
如我所言  有时是威士忌起作用让人说胡话
Like I said, sometimes it's the whisky that does the talking.
他说只有谢尔比兄弟才知道枪存放在哪里
He says only the brothers know where the guns are kept.
丹尼还说过
Well, Danny also says
他看到德国步兵躲在运奶车后面
he sees German infantrymen on the backs of milk carts.
他用他的扫帚柄扫射他们
And he shoots them with his broomstick.
我们在伯明翰轻兵器工厂里有人
We have men in the BSA factory.
他们说枪在你手上
They say it's you who has them.
我们还有人在警局工作
And we have men who work in the police station.
每根手指  谢尔比先生  这座城里的每根手指
Every finger, Mr Shelby, every finger in this city,
都指向同一方向
points in one direction.
请别把我当傻子
Please don't mistake me for a fool.
我直说了吧
Let me get to the point.
我不管你在这里乱搞什么
I don't care what kind of half-arsed tinker operation
该死的吉普赛勾当
you have going here.
但我可以跟你保证
But I can assure you,
我代表一个十分特殊的组织
I represent a very different category of organization.
我表弟被枪击
My cousin was shot.
我是法官  陪审团和行刑者
I am judge, jury and executioner.
我认为你有罪  就由我下判决
I find you guilty and I pass sentence.
你把枪送来给我
You deliver the guns to me
否则我就把你和你那帮暴徒
or I deliver death and hell's fury
送到十八层地狱去
to you and your little tribe of heathens.
我说得够清楚了吗
Am I making myself clear?
我要跟你坦白一些事
Let me confess something to you.
只跟你坦白
And only to you.
枪在我手里
I have the guns...
但对我而言已成负担了
..But they have become a burden to me.
也许现在是时候卸掉负担了
Perhaps it is time to unload that burden.
卖个好价钱
For the right price.
马拉奇·波恩
Malachi Byrne.
南阿玛爱尔兰共和军的旅长
Brigade commander of the South Armagh IRA.
你这回可钓上条大鱼了
You've hooked yourself a big fish there.
拿枪做诱饵  谁知道我们还能钓上什么来
With these guns as bait who knows what we'll catch?
我们
'We'?
你是在提议你我携手合作吗
Are you suggesting that you and I could work together as a team?
也许我们的共同点比你想象的多  督察
Perhaps we have more in common than you think, Inspector.
你能活捉他送过来吗
Can you deliver him?
有你相助就行
With your help.
我要你去爱尔兰放出消息  说与我无关
And I want word put out in Ireland that I was not involved.
我还得为你解决问题
So, I would be solving a problem for you.
而我会为你赢得那枚勋章
And I would be winning you that medal.
如果我得到一枚勋章
If I get a medal
我会把你的姓名首字母刻在后面
I will have your initials engraved on the backside.
我的姓名首字母刻在你屁股后面
My initials on your backside.
那真是让人想入非非的画面
Now, that's quite an image.
督察  既然我们相处得这么好
Inspector, since we are getting along so well,
你能回答我一个问题吗
can you answer me a question?
是谁告诉你弗莱迪·索恩的行踪
Who gave you Freddie Thorne?
城里每个人都知道
As everyone in the city knows.
正是你  谢尔比先生
It was you, Mr Shelby.
你好啊  儿子
Hello, son.
都在这儿了
It's all there.
是啊
It is indeed.
我们要拿这笔钱干一番事业  儿子
We're going to build something with this, son.
伟大的事业
Something magnificent.
我们什么时候出发  老爸
When do we sail, Dad?
-渴望开工了  是吗  -对啊
- Hungry for work, are you? - Yeah.
这周五有艘船要出海  拳击台见
A ship sails Friday. Meet me at the boxing ring.
好  周五
Right. Friday.
周五
Friday.
门留着别关
Leave that open.
不用了
No.
-你预感麻烦要找上门来了吗  -对
- Are you expecting trouble? - Yeah.
-在这个点吗  -半夜跟其他时候没两样
- At this hour? - Midnight is as good an hour as any.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
圣安德鲁的钟声在半夜敲响时
When the St Andrew's bell strikes midnight,
两名爱尔兰共和军成员将穿过那道门
two IRA men are going to come through that door.
等他们获得他们想要的东西后  就会动手杀我
When they have what they want, they plan to kill me.
你的任务就是阻止那一切
It's your job to stop that happening.
你可以早些给我警告的
You could have given me some warning.
我也是才得到消息的
I just got the message myself.
他们想在这里单独见我
They want to meet me here alone.
酒吧女招待不算人吗
And barmaids don't count?
不算  酒吧女招待不算
No. Barmaids don't count.
你得去密室待会儿
Now, you're going to be in the back room.
我要坐在那里
I am going to be sitting there.
等我开始祝酒时
When I make a toast,
你就举着那玩意儿出来
you're going to come out with that thing raised.
你别开枪  指着就行  剩下的我来
You don't shoot, you just point, I'll do the rest.
你会杀了他们吗
Will you kill them?
-不会  警察要活的  -警察也知道这事吗
- No, the police want them alive... - The police know about this?
听着  你把枪举起来
Look, you just hold it up
指着就行  好吗
and you just point. Right?
好了  快快快  快  走吧
Right, go, go. Go on, go.
我们就躲在这儿
We'll hold back here.
无论哪一方受伤  都与我们无关
If damage is done to either side, it's no concern of ours.
你们不渴了吗
Lost your thirst, eh?
给我们看看在哪儿
Just show us where.
给我现金
Give me the cash.
你们需要一把铲子
You're going to need a shovel.
你个该死的笨吉普赛人
You thick fucking tinker.
你以为我们会让你活命吗
Did you think we'd let you live?
进行最后的忏悔吧  谢尔比先生
Make your peace, Mr Shelby.
我会以我自己的方式忏悔
I will make my peace my own way.
敬不算在内的酒吧女招待
To barmaids who don't count...
你为什么要开枪
Why did you shoot?
你为什么要开枪  格蕾丝
Why did you shoot, Grace?
我不知道我有那样可怕的心理
I didn't know I had it in me like that.
现在你看到我的真实面目了
So, now you've seen me.
你也看到了真实的我
And you've seen me...
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
你们本该在时钟敲响第六下时就赶到
You were supposed to come on the sixth chime.
你们本该在他妈的第六声钟响就赶到的
You were supposed to come on the fucking sixth chime.
他们不肯投降
They refused to surrender.
他们擅长战斗  他们很勇敢
They fought well. They were brave men.
他看起来像是被某个凶猛的野兽咬死的
Well, he looks like he was killed by a wild fucking animal.
不过
Still...
就当这一切都没发生  他们从没来过这里
This never happened and they were never here,
谁在意是怎么死的呢
who cares?
你能把这些尸体弄出去吗
Will you get the bodies out of here?
他们让这位女士反胃了吗
All right, are they...? Are they making the lady uncomfortable?
我就不打扰你们这对小情人了  好吗
I'll leave you two love birds to it then, eh?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
首先我要澄清  我不知道
First of all, let me say I had no idea
他会让你卷入这宗丑陋的交易中
he would involve you in this ugly business.
我要是早知道  绝不会坐视不管
If I had, I never would have let it happen.
他信任我  我告诉过你
He trusts me. I told you that.
你不相信我
You didn't believe me.
莫斯警长提交了案件报告
Sergeant Moss made a report.
当然  我已经烧掉了
Which, of course, I have burnt.
他说当他进去时  你们正抱在一起
He said that when he entered the room, you were embracing.
那是你关注的要点吗  一个拥抱
Is that your primary concern? An embrace?
我  我关心的是你的利益
My...my concern is your welfare.
是我杀的他们
It was me who killed them.
我失控了
I had no control.
你和一群暴徒生活在一起
You have been living with beasts.
试图阻止我的人正是那个暴徒
It was the beast that tried to stop me.
我相信昨晚改变了我内心的某些想法
I believe last night something inside me changed.
我不再想为父亲报仇了
I no longer feel the need to avenge my father.
促使我来到这里的怨恨烟消云散
The hatred that I brought with me here has gone.
于是我接受这项任务的初衷也不存在了
And therefore my reasons for joining the service.
你想辞职吗
You want to resign?
我想我们的任务已经结束了
I think our mission has come to a natural end.
我想我知道枪藏在哪里了
I think I know where the guns are hidden.
你知道了  那么  告诉我在哪里
You do? So? Tell me where.
如果我是对的  枪找到了
If I am right, and the guns are found,
你与汤玛斯·谢尔比再无瓜葛
you will have no more business with Thomas Shelby.
不是吗  我们的军事任务也完成了
Is that not so? Our military mission will be over.
我们怎么来的就怎么走
And we can leave the city as we found it.
你是在试图  和我做交易码
Are you trying to... do a deal with me?
如果是的话  你就得说明白点
Because if you are, you must be explicit.
我要你保证  如果枪找到了
I want your word that Thomas Shelby will not be harmed
你不能伤害汤玛斯·谢尔比
if the guns are recovered.
君子一言  驷马难追
Your word as a gentleman.
怎么样
Will you give it?
你  为什么想救他
Why...would you want to save him?
残留的同情心
A residue of sympathy.
同情心  你是说感情
Sympathy? You mean sentiment?
是的
Yes.
他以他的方式  对我很好
In his way, he has been kind to me.
感情
Sentiment.
没错
Yes.
你太善良了不适合这份工作
You are too good-hearted for this work.
也许吧
Perhaps.
所以为了我  你能放过他吗
So, for my sake, will you spare him?
我向你保证
You have my word.
在盗窃案发生一周后
A week after the robbery
圣安德鲁斯墓地有一场葬礼
there was a burial at St Andrews' churchyard.
我发现那个本该被安葬的人还活着
I have found out the man supposed to be buried is alive.
亚瑟心里藏不住事
Arthur is quite transparent.
我得知那场葬礼只有谢尔比家的兄弟们参加
I learned that the funeral was attended only by the brothers.
那个墓穴挖的远比正常情况深得多
And the grave that was dug was far deeper than your average
内部还含有铅
and was lined with lead...
为了保持干燥
To keep out the damp.
枪就被埋在那个墓穴中
The guns are buried in that grave.
那么  今晚我们去掘墓
Then, tonight, we will dig up the grave.
*当家人以为我安全入睡时*
*When my family thinks that I'm safely in my bed*
*从黎明直至黑夜*
*Oh, from morn until night*
*我倚着你的头*
*I am stretched out at your head*
*在六尺之下呼唤我*
*Calling out unto the earth*
*带着激动狂热的泪水*
*With tears hot and wild*
*为那个男孩的逝去*
*For the loss of a boy*
*从孩提时代起我挚爱的男孩*
*That I loved as a child*
乖  乖乖快点睡觉吧
Please, please go to sleep.
*我躺在你的坟墓上*
*So, I am stretched on your grave*
*永远躺在这里*
*And I'll lie here for ever*
*执子之手*
*If your hands were in mine*
*永不分离*
*I'd be sure they would not sever*
*我的苹果树  我的光明*
*My apple tree, my brightness*
*是时候在一起了*
*It's time we were together...*
干得漂亮  小伙子们
Well done, boys!
*我带着泥土的芳香*
*For I smell of the earth*
*我穿着当季的衣裳*
*And I'm worn by the weather *
除了一把枪不在  其余的都找到了
All, but one gun accounted for.
长官  我请求辞职
Then, Sir, I resign my commission.
好
Good.
那么  我不再是你的上司
So, I am no longer your superior officer
你也不再是我的下属了
and you are no longer my subordinate.
既然如此
And therefore...
法规允许我
Regulations permit me...
送给你这个
to offer you this.
我  我是个简单的好人
I am...I am a simple man, but a good man.
我对你的欣赏
And my admiration for you...
转化成为爱
Has turned to love.
我不是恳求你也爱我  只是
I don't ask for love in return. Just...
鉴于我们志趣相投
Recognition that we are like minds...
有共同的价值观
With shared values.
格蕾丝
Grace...
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
坎贝尔先生
Mr Campbell...
你值得拥有更好的人
You deserve better.
你不答应是因为他吗
Is it him between us?
那个掘墓之徒  是他吗
Is it the beast that dug that grave? Is it him?
我明早递交辞呈
My resignation will be with you in the morning...
爸
Dad!
你好儿子  谁告诉你我在这里的
Hullo, son. May I ask who gave my whereabouts?
马斯顿
Marston.
他说你昨晚付完嫖资就离开了
Said you left him last night with a bill for your whores.
好吧  至少我们能道别  儿子
Well, at least we got to say goodbye, son.
替我向你亲爱的兄弟们说声再见  好吗
And bid a fond adieu to your dear brothers, would you?
你怎能这样对我们
How could you do this to us?
哪样  儿子
Do what, son?
你说的那些话  谢尔比赌场
All that stuff you said about...the Shelby Casino...
大西洋城
..and Atlantic City.
说实话
Well, if the truth be told,
我并没去过美国
I've not been so acquainted with that promised land
我全是骗你的
as I had thee believe.
你是个他妈的骗子和盗贼
You're a fucking liar and a thief.
把我的钱还我
You give me back my fucking money.
"盗若因饿  窃物充饥
"Do not despise the thief, if he steals to
人之不鄙"
"satisfy his starvation"
这是《圣经》箴言  儿子
That's in the Holy Bible, son.
我已经饿太久了
And I've starved for so very long.
再见了  儿子
Fare thee well, son.
我等你了
I waited for you.
我等了
I waited.
听着  小子  这里不是拳击场
Listen to me, boy. You are not in the prize ring now.
你再敢动我一根毫毛
If you ever put your hands on me again,
我会割了你的喉咙  把你丢到铁轨上
I'll cut your fucking throat and spread you on these tracks.
你父亲呢
Where's your father?
我猜他正用那双玩弄妓女的脏手
I'm assuming he's busy frittering the 500 you took from us
挥霍你从我们家偷拿的五百英镑
and put in his thieving, whore-groping hands.
你怎么想的
What were you thinking?
做这种事前
How dare you do something
为什么不跟汤玛斯和我商量
like that without talking to Thomas or me?
汤米知道了吗
Does Tommy know?
不知道  但你得告诉他
No. But you're going to tell him.
伟大的胜利值得庆祝
You might take satisfaction in a great victory.
可怕的后果得以避免
A terrible consequence has been avoided.
我们挖出来的那些枪
'Those guns that we dug up
永远不会被用于谋杀无辜
will never be used to murder the innocent
或颠覆政府
'or usurp the status quo.
但是  尽管我们阻止了犯罪
'But, even though we have solved a crime,
但却没能将凶手绳之于法
'we have as yet failed to punish the criminal.'
挖坟埋枪的人
This man who dug that grave
也给自己掘下坟墓
has also dug his own.
事实证明  他对国家是一个致命的威胁
He has proved a deadly menace to the King's peace.
今晚我们将击溃他
'And tonight we will strike him down.
我们将用剑直刺他的黑心
'We will drive our swords through his black heart,
我们将端掉他肮脏的鼠窝
'we will pursue him into the rat holes that he infests.'
最终
And, finally,
我们要让他和同党在城中消失
we will rid this city of his kind.
正义必将伸张  我们绝不放弃
Justice will be done and will be seen to be done.
阿门
Amen.
今后我们会有麻烦  芬恩
There's going to be trouble now, Finn.
你照顾好自己  听到了吗
You look after yourself, do you hear me?
我会离开一段时间  好的  走吧
I'm going to be going away for a while. Right... Go on.
喂  谁他妈想打一架
Right... Who wants to fucking fight?
拳击赛结束了  我们要关门离开了
Fighting's over. We're closing up and moving on.
我问谁他妈想打架
I said who wants to fucking fight?
老子是他妈的亚瑟·谢尔比
My name is Arthur fucking Shelby!
谁敢跟我打
Who dares to fight me?!
回家吧伙计  小心被揍
Go home, lad. Before you catch yourself a spanking.
我在迪格巴思的兄弟说从达林顿
My brother in Digbeth just says the police are coming down
来了大批警察
from Deritend in numbers.
到处寻找汤米·谢尔比
Asking for Tommy Shelby by name.
见鬼
Shit.
-我得避避风头  -为什么
- I'm going to have to lie low for a while. - Why?
我没筹码了
I lost my bargaining power.
那个警察  现在我和他只有一个人能活命
This copper, it's just me and him now.
我回来后
When I get back...
我要告诉你一些事
..I'll tell you some things.
哈里说警察已经到迪格巴思了
Harry said the police are already in Digbeth.
-是的  -你为什么冒险来这里
- Yeah. - You took a chance coming here, why?
警察进巷子了  汤米
The police are in the lane, Tommy.
跟我走
Come with me.
我在找汤玛斯·谢尔比
I'm looking for Thomas Shelby.
没听说过这人
Never heard of him.
你永远别想找到他
You'll never find him.
回家去
Go home.
也许我该再问一遍
Perhaps I should ask the question again.
跪下
On your knees.
现在  听清楚了  酒保
Now, understand this, barman.
我不关心你的死活
I don't care if you live or die.
我真不知道
I don't know.
他离开了
He left...
跟酒吧女侍一起
..with the barmaid.
他和格蕾丝走了
He left with Grace.
我觉得他们去她家了
I think they were going to her place.
取消行动
Call it off.
我不明白  长官  我们应该去找酒吧女侍...
I don't understand, sir. We should find the barmaid...
全部取消
Call it all off!
都取消
All of it!
上车
Get in.
比较简陋
It's not much of a place.
挺好的
It's all right.
喝茶吗
You want tea?
不了
Tea? No.
我有朗姆酒
I have rum...
我还是喝茶吧
Actually, tea it is.
你想让我刮目相看
You want to impress me?
是的  你有饼干吗
Yes. And do you have a biscuit?
没有  饼干引老鼠
No. They attract mice.
人一回家感觉就不一样了
People look different at home.
怎么不一样
In what way?
卸下警惕
Off guard.
我应该警惕吗
Should I be on my guard?
不用  我只是个喝茶的男人
No, I'm a man who drinks tea.
风声过去后  我就走
When the trouble dies down, I'll go.
你觉得什么时候会过去
When will it die down, do you think?
晚些时候吧
Late, I would say.
那明早之前都不会走了
So, not until the morning then.
是的  明早之前都不会
Yes. I'd say I'll be here till morning.
你有一架留声机
You have a gramophone?
已经坏了
It's broken.
那我们也能跳舞
We could still dance.
是啊  当然
Yes. Why not.
我知道你喜欢正式的邀请
I know you like to be asked properly.
格蕾丝  我能请你跳支舞吗
Grace, can I have this dance?
你还好吗
Are you ok?
我没有听见铲子挖墙的声音
I don't hear the shovels against the wall.
什么铲子
What shovels?
你能帮助我吗
Will you help me?
帮助你什么
Help you with what?
所有的事
With everything...
所有这些操蛋的事
..The whole fucking thing.
操蛋的人生
Fucking life...
生意
..Business.
我找到了你
I've found you.
你也找到了我
And you found me.
我们互相帮助
We'll help each other.
我们在天上的父
Our Father, who art in heaven.
愿人都尊你的名为圣
Hallowed be thy name....
给丘吉尔先生发一封电报
Send a telegram to Mr Churchill...
告诉他我有好消息  很好的消息
I have news, very good news.
告诉他我的工作已经完成
Tell him the business I came to attend to is now complete.
我要离开这里了
I'll be leaving the city.
但在此之前  还有一件事要做
There's just one matter I need to tidy up first.
波莉都告诉你了吧
Polly told you?
你应该选择用枪的
You should have used a gun.
你是在嘲笑我吗  汤米
Are you laughing at me, Tommy?
就在一切将要走上正轨的时候  亚瑟
Just when things are starting to go right, Arthur...
你竟然做出这种轻生之事
you try and do this.
你不喜欢盛大的派对吗
Don't you like fancy parties?
或者
Or, um...
香槟还有跑车
..Champagne or fast cars?
或者这个怎么样
Or how about this...?
印有你名字的名片
Your name on a business card.
谢尔比
Shelby...
兄弟有限公司
..Brothers Limited.
亚瑟·谢尔比
Arthur Shelby.
赌马公司合伙人
Associate bookmaker.
我今早才从印刷厂取回来
I just had them picked up from the printers this morning.
你是三位合伙人之一
You're one of three shareholders.
你  我还有约翰  根据法律
Me, you and John, and according to the law,
我们是平等合伙人
we are equal partners...
这可都是白纸黑字写着的
and it's written on the paperwork in black and white.
三分之一  三分之一  三分之一
A third, a third, a third.
但是
But the thing is...
我和约翰也很愿意平分你的股份
well, me and John quite fancy splitting your share so,
所以下一次记得用枪
just next time, use a gun, man.
我们在警察局里的人说  那个警长要走了
Our men at the station tell me that copper is leaving town.
我们没事了
We're in the clear.
我们正在一步一步往上爬  兄弟
We are on our way up in the world, brother.
相信我
Believe me.